<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Sample</string>
    <string name="long_text">To display a different animation from the default screen slide animation, implement the ViewPager.PageTransformer interface and supply it to the view pager. The interface exposes a single method, transformPage(). At each point in the screens transition, this method is called once for each visible page (generally theres only one visible page) and for adjacent pages just off the screen. For example, if page three is visible and the user drags towards page four, transformPage() is called for pages two, three, and four at each step of the gesture.

In your implementation of transformPage(), you can then create custom slide animations by determining which pages need to be transformed based on the position of the page on the screen, which is obtained from the position parameter of the transformPage() method.

The position parameter indicates where a given page is located relative to the center of the screen. It is a dynamic property that changes as the user scrolls through the pages. When a page fills the screen, its position value is 0. When a page is drawn just off the right side of the screen, its position value is 1. If the user scrolls halfway between pages one and two, page one has a position of -0.5 and page two has a position of 0.5. Based on the position of the pages on the screen, you can create custom slide animations by setting page properties with methods such as setAlpha(), setTranslationX(), or setScaleY().

When you have an implementation of a PageTransformer, call setPageTransformer() with your implementation to apply your custom animations. For example, if you have a PageTransformer named ZoomOutPageTransformer, you can set your custom animations like this:

ViewPager mPager = (ViewPager) findViewById(R.id.pager);
...
mPager.setPageTransformer(true, new ZoomOutPageTransformer());
See the Zoom-out page transformer and Depth page transformer sections for examples and videos of a PageTransformer.

Zoom-out page transformer

This page transformer shrinks and fades pages when scrolling between adjacent pages. As a page gets closer to the center, it grows back to its normal size and fades in.</string>
</resources>
